Tyler Dan said they didn't explore it,
but
>> yeah. So, I mean that that's an
interesting question and I don't want to
like get into all the specifics of all
the guys we we we talk about because you
guys know like John like we we have
conversations all the time and the you
never want those things to get out right
with with if you're talking about
different players whether you're trading
for them or trading looking to trade
them away. A lot of times you're not
even looking to trade them. It's just
teams will inquire about guys. So,
you're going to have these
conversations. sometimes they get out,
but that's our personnel department's
job is to know what's out there both
coming in and going out. So, um, without
getting into specifics, Tyler, you know,
we we we explore everything and, um,
ultimately that was a decision we
thought was would be best for the team
to move on.
>> So, are you able to explain on why did
you feel it was the best? You know, he
had a year left on his deal. What really
went into what did that think? Yeah, I
think again I really don't want to get
into specifics and and we've talked with
Tyler about that and so um but I will
say is like he was one of our first guys
that we signed and um he really, you
know, really appreciate, you know, what
he did for us the last two years and
wish him a lot of luck in LA and and I
think he's going to do well there. But
um in terms of the specifics, I think we
just keep those in house.
>> What do you feel looking at the edge
rushers that was a big priority coming
in? How do you feel about how things
went there um and what you ended up with
and what does that do for you guys?
>> Yeah, really excited about the guys we
brought in, the guys we have and so um
that was certainly a point of emphasis
to get there and to get OA to get Casey
and we still have the guys that we have
in the building. Um just really that
that was something we needed to address
and we did. So, uh, um, I was actually
like pretty surprised we were able to
get both of those guys and at the
especially with I thought that Caleb on
would be a little bit more. Um, but, you
know, I think because we were patient on
some things, we were able to kind of sit
back and wait, let some things come to
us. And I think, you know, he's going to
be motivated because he's still really
young. He's still really, you know, he's
still ascending. So, I think he's got
one year to prove it. And I think he's
going to do really well. obviously
getting OA long term and he's the same
way where we think he's still ascending
and um and so super excited about all
that. You
>> guys obviously always have contingency
plans. How many contingency plans did
you have to get into if you guys did
make plays for Pierce or Porto Linder
Bomb some of those guys and then still
spend 100 million onway?
>> We were still able to spend a lot. Um
but yeah, I mean you have to you have to
have all those plans, right? because you
don't ever know that free agency is very
unpredictable and so um you know you
think you can have the best situation
that you know the the right people the
right coaches the right scheme for
somebody and and they still don't come
to you for whatever reason that is and
sometimes it's a great reason sometimes
you don't think it's as good of a reason
but you can't count on that so um you
really kind of just go down the line and
just always keep your options open and I
think there was a point there where we
made a couple signings and okay let's
just sit back and reassess and see where
we're at and let some things come to us
and and that's what happened this year.
We were able to get some guys that I
didn't think we're going to be able to
get and really happy that we got
as many draft picks this year obviously
had the seventh overall pick but um
traded some of those with some deals the
last few years. Did that make you more
aggressive in free agency just knowing
that you wouldn't have as many shots at
it in April?
>> Yeah, I think it was just more we needed
to bring a lot of good players in. So
obviously um with fewer picks you know
you're not going to have as you know we
don't have a second we don't have a
fourth for Laramie which you know fine
with that you know but um you know so
you do have those holes in the draft but
I don't I think it's just more we just
needed to get some good players in here
and guys that that fit our play style
and I think uh did a really good job of
working together with the coaches to to
achieve that.
>> How do you feel the the receivers room
is now? Is that a a place where you
still would like to add or kind of
what's your view of that?
>> Yeah, I think I mean really every room
is is a room we'd still like to add. I
mean it's March 30th right now. So um
but in terms of that room specifically,
I mean obviously we have Terry. Terry's
number one receiver. Um we brought Tayen
back which I'm really excited about. I
think he's got another level to go to.
Um he showed us a lot you know at
practice and in the games when he was
able to to make some plays there. Luke
and Jaylen, another couple guys that
are, you know, a year older and we're
excited about and then bringing Tiam
back and Van, we have a couple young
guys in there, too. So, I like the room
right now, but I think just like
everywhere, um, you know, we have a lot
of time to add before we play in
September.
>> How high priority was it to get a little
bit more athleticism in the middle of
the field? Um, with the lineback with
bringing Leo and and him working with
Lulu and company.
>> Yeah, I think it's really more
athleticism everywhere, you know. not
just the middle of the field, but
certainly um wanted to be faster. And so
Leo definitely fits that bill and and
really most of the guys we brought in
fit that bill in terms of that. So um
you know, the whole reason we signed him
was just because that that clip where he
jumped up on the bus, that was it for
me. Did you guys see that? It's
unbelievable.
>> No, but I mean that it speaks to his
athleticism, but he's he's certainly
another guy who we think has another
level to him, you know? He's he's he's
hungry. he really wanted to be with us.
And uh he's versatile, so he can play on
the edge of the line of scrimmage. He
can play off the ball. He was a really
good special teams player. He can drop
in coverage. So um his athleticism, his
versatility, and and his he's young and
and he's hungry to prove that he can um
be a better player than he was at the
Chiefs, which he was pretty good.
>> Understanding how fluid the draft is,
how much does what you've done in free
agency impact what you do, especially
early on. Yeah, I think, you know, one
of the things we wanted to do was make
it so we don't have to force a pick,
right? We don't have to pick for knee.
We don't have to pick a certain
position. So, uh, we're in that position
now. So, it's really just, you know,
especially with that pick number seven's
a big pick. And so, um, just finding
someone who can really impact our team,
you know, impact our team right away and
impact our team long term. So, whoever
that is, and there's a lot of good
players in there, but um with what we
did in free agency, it's not like, okay,
we have to go get this because we have a
gaping hole here or there. And you guys
can debate on, you know, where we need
to add and all that, and I understand
that, but for where we sit, we don't
feel like we need to reach for anything
right now.
>> Is it harder to get a feel for what
teams like doing this draft compared to
other years? Do you have a different at
this point in the time, do you have a
sense or is it harder than previous
years? Yeah, that's a great question
because I I I feel that way. Like I I
have no idea who's going to be there at
seven right now. I mean, there's a
couple guys that I know are going to be
gone, but then how that goes after that,
I don't know. And it changes every week.
You know, I think if you look at a mock
draft this week, next week, the next
week, it's kind of changed. So, um,
it'll probably get a little more clear
as we get closer to the draft. And
obviously, we're still right in the
middle of our draft meeting. So, the
more work you can put in, we still have
a lot of touch points for the guys. We
have 30 visits coming in. So, kind of
getting an understanding of the
landscape and and who these guys are
even a little bit more. But, um, yeah,
it's a mystery to me right now. And so,
we just got to be ready for anybody.
>> Because of that, does that make it
harder to maybe have teams move around
in that first round?
>> Yeah, I I honestly don't. Without having
a ton of quarterbacks, I don't know
there's going to be a lot of moving
around or moving back. I wouldn't
anticipate it. You don't really see that
happening. um unless it's for a
quarterback because it's pretty costly
to do that if you want to move up. But
um so yeah, I I haven't heard much about
that in terms of guys teams moving
around.
>> Given how few running backs have been
taken as high as seven, would you have
any trepidation about taking one there?
>> I I mean I wouldn't have any trepidation
about taking anyone at seven that I
think can really help our team that we
think can really help our team. Um but
you know also we got Bill in the seventh
round last year so you can get the you
can get running backs at a lot of
different ways. Um but certainly if we
think that any running back or any
really position no matter what it is if
it's a you know there's there's the
premium positions as people would say
and there's positions that are maybe
less premium depending on who you ask.
Um but if that person can impact your
team in a certain way then you would
take them you know regardless of their
position. You said uh when you asked
Jade that you knew pretty early on that
this is for you.
>> Understanding that teams one through six
will determine the board. Do you know
right now who you would want to take if
you were given the choice?
>> No.
>> With the mysterious nature of this
draft, I guess, and maybe this is silly,
but when you guys go to prodays, you
guys have guys in for your visits.
>> Is there ever any thought of we don't
want to tip people off about who we want
to bring in because nobody really knows
what's going to happen? Yeah, I think
there's there's definitely strategy to
that in terms of how much time or um you
know how much work you put into certain
guys, but at the same time you also want
to know as much as you can about these
guys. Have as many touch points as you
can. So does that mean you don't do a 30
visit because of that? Because then
you're missing an opportunity to spend
time with them, you know, and our scouts
have done an excellent job starting
really in in August all the way until
now of getting as much information as
possible. But, um, you know, as we go
through that process, we're still
learning about these guys. We're still
asking questions and learning new
things. And there's guys that I haven't
seen. There's guys that DQ hasn't seen
that we'd like to spend some time with.
So, to me, that's a great question that
that outweighs the kind of cloak and
dagger element of not bringing guys in.
We've done I've done that past where we
did. We just didn't talk to somebody
after the combine when we picked them.
Um, but I don't know, you know, how much
that's, you know, how much that really
matters. Like, does does the team at
number five really care who we like,
right? I mean, I hope not. Hope they
hate the
>> Yeah, but I mean, enough to to trade up.
I don't know.
>> There's a lot of conversation about some
of the guys at the top of this draft are
at non premium positions, including like
a running back. And part of the
conversation is like, well, the
economics of it, like if you draft that
player that like it's it's just not as
the the the price later on especially is
not as high as some other ones.
Therefore, maybe it's not making a good
value play from a salary cap
perspective. Does that matter to you at
all or just adjust the tone?
>> You you consider it. Yeah. But you just
I really consider more how much they can
impact us and you know talking with our
coaches, talking with the staff and the
other scouts like, okay, how much can
this player impact us? you know, and
whether you're saying whether you're
saying it's a running back, whether it's
a safety, whether it's a linebacker that
are nonp premium positions, but at the
same time, like I I have Fred Warner in
San Francisco and I can't tell you how
much that guy impacted our team. Um, and
so like there are, you know, there are
exceptions to that and and so I think I
think you're kind of you can overthink
it by doing that sometimes, but just I
would like to say take the best player
who can help us now and in the future
and worry about the second contract
later.
>> We know that you've made a priority of
involving the coordinators and the
coaches. How's that relationship kind of
evolved into your third draft? Uh, it's
been like in terms of I'll just speak on
the guys we have right now with with
Dvonte and David and they've been
fantastic. They've been really really
good. Got a chance to we went to Ohio
State together, but during the draft
meetings, during the free agency
meetings, there's been really a ton of
open dialogue which has been really good
learning because we just need to learn
need to learn what they're trying to do,
how they're trying to use certain guys,
and that'll give us the answers, you
know, to bring up certain guys for them.
And and the back and forth has been
really fun. Those guys, both of them are
really smart. They're really really
smart. They're really good guys and um
they really want to collaborate. So,
it's been really good so far.
>> How do you balance immediate impact
versus growth potential? Is it as simple
as early in the draft? I want someone
that can help right away and then as the
draft goes on or would you be open is
are you more open to having somebody
that has that ability to grow even if
it's earlier in the draft?
>> Yeah, I think I think you know picking
at seven, you know, you'd hope you get
somebody that can help you right away.
You know, I think other times if if you
look into the later parts of the draft,
there's some guys that aren't going to
help you right away depending on who you
have there and where they are in their
development. So, I think you weigh that
a little bit more later in the draft.
But, I think picking on the top 10, you
really want to get somebody who can come
in and play right away and impact your
team.
>> Have to ask about Jaden. Um,
>> just everything he dealt with last
season, was there, um, any concern about
him participating in the final football
game? Did you watch it?
>> Yeah, I try not to watch too much of it,
but we t I mean we we talked about this
really for gosh, when did it start when
the thing came out? Maybe in September.
So, we we've had an open dialogue with
Jaden about that throughout. And so,
obviously, you're concerned. I think all
of us probably concerned about that. Not
just me, probably me the most, but but
um understanding that something that was
important to him and you know, just
talking about the risk and the risk
versus reward and all that. and then
he's got to make the decision on his own
in terms of that. But we supported
whatever he wanted to do. And you know,
he lo the thing about Jane, he loves
football. He loves playing. He loves
competing. And um so, you know, I think
that was something that was important to
him. So, I'm glad he did it. I'm glad he
came out.
>> Um N quadrant situation in Baltimore.
What can the league do that maybe could
prevent that situation from unfolding in
the future?
>> Oh, man.
>> Is there anything? I I don't know. I
mean that that's hard to answer. That's
a big long philosophical question that
I'm just
>> You don't want to be philosophical?
>> Yeah. No, not right now.
>> Can you was there anything you do with
the physicals that would because that it
came down to a lot about that and
>> I you know I don't know all the
specifics of that. you know, obviously,
um,
you know, th those two teams had had
talked and and they understood what what
his health situation was, but I don't
know in terms of the nitty-gritty what
what went down there. But certainly um,
it does give you pause, you know, and
um, you know, I don't I don't know
there's there's a great answer for it
though, John. Otherwise, they would have
probably had it already. I'm not like
the answer guy. more like
>> just
generally just what was your reaction
when
>> um you know my reaction honestly as I
felt bad for Max, you know, I felt bad
for Max going to a new team and and and
this is nothing to do with the the
Ravens or or the Raiders. First of all,
those are both great GMs, guys that are
friends of mine, so I'm not going to get
into who was right and who was wrong,
but I just felt bad for Max in terms of,
you know, going somewhere and and that
happening to him. But, you know, also I
think it's a cool opportunity for him to
go back to the Raiders now. So,
>> got time for one more.
>> You guys so far in your tenure here have
kept a fair amount of cap space. You
right now have a lot obviously you could
still make more moves, but like what's
the your general thought of what how you
want to use your cap space? Because I
think there's some thought of like, hey,
you guys have Jade under working
contract, just go nuts. What why why do
you kind of go the way you've been doing
it? Yeah, I mean, first of all, I want
to hand it to to Brandon and Rob for um
we're in a really healthy cap situation
and it's really good and and that's uh
on purpose. Um but also understand that
we spent a lot of money. We spent a ton
of money. So, it's not like we're not
spending, but we're also doing a really
good job staying in a healthy cap. That
way that does give us the ability if we
want to make make a move, we can make a
move. But it really keeps us so we're
not having to make decisions that aren't
that aren't the best decisions for the
team because they're based on the cap.
And you've seen that with teams, you
know, recently where there's certain
things they they want to do or try to
do, but they can't do because of their
cap situation. So, we're um this helps
us really now, but also in the future as
well.
>> I think you're part of this because I'm
not I can't even balance my own bank
account. Is there some notion of like
taking some of the money you spend in
the years to come and spending it now if
you have the space so later on you're
not, you know, in a in a situation where
you you have to make some calls based on
the cap?
>> Uh I mean that's one way to look at it,
but I I think I'll go back to that we
we've spent a ton already. We spent a
lot a lot of money and um so you know
there there is you do have we we've we
have great ownership and they've been
really supportive uh of Dan and me in
terms of what we've wanted to do and
they've they've been able to do a ton of
things in terms of not only on the field
players but off the field with what
we've done with our facility and
everything like that. So at the same
time you also want to be smart and not
overspend. So um you know I think that
all goes into it as well.
>> Just briefly that last Thank you. Like
how how much difference is there in the
way you and Sasa and like NFL people
approach the cap and spending and
contracts versus the way fans and media
look at over the cap? Like how different
are those?
>> They're pretty different. They're pretty
different.
>> So I mean it is a little misleading at
times when when you're looking at that
and but it does say that we you know we
do have flexibility. But uh in terms of
if you look at what we've spent over the
last few years um we've spent a lot and
so we've been really aggressive in terms
of acquiring players and doing the
things we need to do to to be
competitive and Josh has given us that
opportunity and flexibility. So I think
you know there's a lot that's not in
that website you know that that that
goes into what we've been doing. What?
So what just for
Sorry. Sorry.
>> So interesting.
>> I know. So like is does that is cash the
biggest thing or is it structure or like
kind of what do you
>> Yeah. I think it's it's what you're
spending like cash you know
year-over-year and you know I mean don't
want to get into a big old another
philosophical debate here but I mean
teams are most teams spend you know over
over the like cash over cap. you know,
they spend over um whatever the cap is
for that year and we do too. And so um
but at the same time like you have you
do have to have some constraints
otherwise you're going to go crazy and
then what happens is you put yourself in
a bad position down the road. It does
catch up to you. It's like a credit
card. It catches up to you at some
point.
>> So I've never had credit card issues but
never
>> Is it fun spending other people's money?
That's way more
when you ever hear I know you don't pay
attention a lot to things that are said
but like when you see reports and people
talk about the cap or things you're like
that is insane that doesn't make any
sense so you like
>> I don't that stuff
>> but seriously that first week of free
agency probably close to a hund00
million in cash was committed that week
>> and I don't think that people understand
that
>> yeah it was we spent a lot of money so
what we like third or something third
yeah so Um yeah, that that gets that
probably gets lost a little bit, but um
I am happy with where we're at. You
know,
>> that's kept ripping you guys for not
spending.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I was funny. I And he he told me
afterwards, but I was like the worst on
Monday
>> of free agency.
Yeah. For the first few hours
>> pure pandemonium.
>> I'm really glad I didn't see any of
that.
>> I can't imagine you're on social media.
>> Yeah. No, I got Sean. Sean, I was and
then uh smartly I'm off. So
>> definitely.
>> Yeah.
>> Now I gotta find the burner.
>> Yeah. No burner.
>> No. I've never sent one tweet. Never in
my life. So
>> you're not missing anything.
>> Never said you didn't have an account.
>> I did. I do. I do have an account. I do
have an account, but I' it's off my
phone now. I don't have the app on my
phone, which is very nice.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, guys.